Guide to the Delmore Schwartz Papers
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
- Personal and Professional Papers, 1936-1966, undated; Series IV; 2.25; (4 boxes)
  This series contains personal and professional papers of Schwartz. The papers reflect the emotionally rife proceedings of his divorces from Gertrude Buckman and Elizabeth Pollet, his problematic financial responsibilities, and his teaching. Other papers include personal papers and drawings.
  - Divorce
    - Note of Issue for Inquest for Gertrude Buckman and Schwartz's divorce, 1944 (Box 21, Folder 823)
    - Notes regarding Pollet and Dr. Gruenthal, 1951-1965, undated (Box 21, Folder 823a)
      Includes photograph of Pollet
    - Letters from lawyers, 1958-1959 (Box 21, Folder 824)
    - Character testimonial regarding Schwartz by unidentified individual, 1959 January 14 (Box 21, Folder 825)
    - Legal documents, statements, and letters, 1958-1961 (Box 21, Folder 826-836)
  - Financial
    - Invoices, 1957-1962 (Box 21, Folder 837-838)
    - Tax statements and notes, 1947, 1958-1959, undated (Box 21, Folder 839)
    - Medical bills, 1958-1966 (Box 21, Folder 840)
    - Housing invoices and notices, 1958-1965 (Box 21, Folder 841)
      Includes eviction notices
    - Bank statements, 1958-1966 (Box 21, Folder 842-848)
    - Home insurance memorandum, 1959 (Box 21, Folder 849)
    - Summons from Syracuse University Hospital, 1965 (Box 21, Folder 850)
  - Teaching
    - Harvard University hire notification letters, 1940, 1943 (Box 21, Folder 851)
    - Princeton University Resident Fellow in Creative Writing notification letter, 1952 January 10 (Box 21, Folder 851a)
    - Princeton University phone directory, 1953 (Box 21, Folder 851b)
    - Syracuse University
      - Memos, 1962-1965 (Box 21, Folder 852)
      - Class lists, undated (Box 21, Folder 853)
      - Blom, Lois Ardyn. Various writings, typescripts, 1962 May (Box 21, Folder 854)
      - Friedman, Nancy. "The Locket: An Original Play for Television," typescript, undated (Box 21, Folder 855)
      - Various student writings, 1942, undated (Box 21, Folder 856-858)
      - Syracuse University Library invoices, 1964-1966 (Box 21, Folder 859)
      - Syracuse Book Center invoices, 1965 (Box 21, Folder 860)
  - Other Papers
    - Judgment of Annulment for Elizabeth Pollet and David Way, 1948 (Box 21, Folder 861a)
    - Curriculum Vita, 1954 (Box 21, Folder 861b)
    - New York University registrar record of Schwartz's coursework at various universities, circa 1935 (Box 21, Folder 861c)
    - Harvard University course grades, graduation program, and poetry award, 1936, 1945-1946 (Box 21, Folder 861)
    - Address book, 1959 (Box 21, Folder 862)
    - Drawings of nudes, faces, and houses, October 1961, undated
      One notebook and loose sketches
    - Event announcements, tickets, and menus, 1943-1966, undated (Box 21, Folder 863-872)
      Includes literary, film, music, book, art, and political announcements
    - 1966 Calendar (Box 21, Folder 873)
    - Empty folders and envelopes with Schwartz's labels and notes, circa 1950-1966 (Box 28)
  - Personal Effects
    - Eyeglasses; nail scissors and clippers; magnifying glass; and jewelry box containing jewelry, pins and keys, undated (Box 22)
- Photographs, 1906-circa 1975, undated; Series V; 0.42; (1 box)
  This series consists of snapshots of Delmore Schwartz, his brother and parents, wives, friends, and a small number of unidentified images. Photonegatives created for publication in James Atlas's Delmore Schwartz: The Life of an American Poet are filed at the end.
  - Delmore Schwartz, 1916-1965 (Box 23, Folder 874)
  - Delmore, Rose, and Kenneth Schwartz, 1914-1926 (Box 23, Folder 875)
  - Schwartz with brother Kenneth and father Harry at Coney Island, 1915-1916 (Box 23, Folder 876)
  - Delmore and Kenneth Schwartz, circa 1920 (Box 23, Folder 877)
  - Schwartz at Library of Congress, 1958 February (Box 23, Folder 878)
    One photograph includes Randall Jarrell
  - Harry and Rose Schwartz, 1906-circa 1960 (Box 23, Folder 879)
  - Gertrude Buckman, 1937-1942 (Box 23, Folder 880)
    Includes one slide
  - Elizabeth Pollet, 1923-1955 (Box 23, Folder 881)
    One photograph includes Barbara Pollet
  - Friends, 1939, undated (Box 23, Folder 882)
  - "Sandy/Sandra", circa 1942 (Box 23, Folder 883)
  - Three unidentified women, 1944, 1963 undated (Box 23, Folder 884-886)
  - Unidentified, undated (Box 23, Folder 887)
    Includes negatives
  - Negatives created for inclusion in James Atlas's Delmore Schwartz: The Life of an American Poet, circa 1975 (Box 23, Folder 888)
    Photonegatives by Syracuse University Library and Yale Library
- Oversize, 1; (4 boxes)
  - Clippings not related to Schwartz (in Series II, Writings), 1940-1966, undated (Box 24, Folder 889-894)
  - Clippings not related to Schwartz (in Series II, Writings), 1940-1966, undated (Box 25, Folder 895-901)
  - Clippings on Schwartz (in Series II, Writings), 1940-1966, undated (Box 26, Folder 902-903)
  - Clippings not related to Schwartz (in Series II, Writings), 1940-1966, undated (Box 26, Folder 904-906)
  - "Track Meet" galleys (in Series II, Writings), 1958 (Box 26, Folder 906a)
  - Drawings of nudes, faces, and houses (in Series IV, Professional and Personal Papers), October 1961, undated (Box 26, Folder 907-908)
  - Clippings not related to Schwartz (in Series II, Writings), 1940-1966, undated (Box 27, Folder 909-914)
- Restricted Fragile, 0.42; (1 box)
  Restricted fragile material. Reference surrogates have been substituted in the main files. For further information consult the appropriate curator.
  - Box 12, folder 573 (Box 29)